Effinger School Collection WLU.Coll.0523
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Effinger School Collection
1909-2011
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Anderson, Clinton Lee
Hatcher, Henry A.
WLU.Coll.0523
5 Box
Separated Materials
A complete run of 35 volumes of the Effinger School yearbook "The Wawbeek" (1940-1960) have been removed from this collection and cataloged in WLU's Rare Book collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection contains material received by Mr.Clinton Anderson: 3 boxes with manila envelopes each with an inventory. The collection was compiled primarily by Mr. Anderson and Mr. Hatcher and stored at Mr. Hatcher's House.
Scope and Contents
The Effinger School collection consists of the compiled research of Clinton Lee Anderson and Henry A. Hatcher, co-authors of "Celebrate Effinger, 1922-2010" their published history of the Effinger School in the Collierstown vicinity of Rockbridge County, Virginia. Included within the collection are various records, publications, printed matter from the school, school newspapers, alumni records, photographs, and general history of the school.
Virginia -- Collierstown -- Collierstown Road; Schools; Education, Secondary; School yearbooks; Rural schools; Anderson, Clinton Lee; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.); Hatcher, Henry A.
- Control (Box 1, Folder 0)
- Alumni Miscellaneous, 1979-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Homecoming; Schools -- Alumni and alumnae; Scholarships; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.)
- Alumni Scholarship, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Schools -- Alumni and alumnae; Scholarships; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.)
- Alumni Scholarship, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Alumni Scholarship, 2000-2010 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Andrew M. Myers Papers, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Diplomas; Myers, Andrew M.; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.)
- Biographies and Obituaries, The documents are all from the 2000s, but they describe some 20th century events (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Obituaries; Biography; Strickler, M. P.; Clemmer, Kathryn Weeks; McDaniel, Clarence; Swink, Robert; Hotinger, Ernestine Chittum; Clark, Carmen Ercell; Coleman, Custis L., Dr.; Perrell, Orion; Tardy, Clarence Leitch
- Calendars, 1990-2011 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Calendars
- Effinger Echo, 1960-02-1960-05; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Newspapers; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.)
- Effinger Echo, 1959-02-1959-12; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Effinger Echo, 1958-02-1958-05; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Effinger Echo, 1957-01-1957-12; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Effinger Echo, 1956-02-1956-12; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Effinger Echo, 1955-02-1955-12; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Effinger Echo, 1954-02-1954-12; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Effinger Echo, 1953-02-1953-12; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Effinger Echo, 1952-02-1952-12; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Effinger Echo, 1951-02-1951-12; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Effinger Echo, 1950-05-1950-12; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Effinger Echo, 1948-02-1948-12; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Effinger Echo, 1947-02-1947-12; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Effinger Echo, 1946-04-1946-12; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Effinger Echo, 1945-03-1945-10; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Effinger Echo, 1944-01-1944-11; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Effinger Echo, 1943-01-1943-11; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Effinger Echo, 1942-02-1942-11; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Effinger Echo, 1941-01-1941-11; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Effinger Echo, 1940-10-1940-12; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Effinger Echo, 1937-01; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Effinger Echo Copies, 1935-12-1939-05; Effinger Echo (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Effinger Elementary Handbooks, 1978-1989; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Effinger Elementary Miscellaneous, 1983-2010; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Newspapers
- Effinger High School, 1976-2012 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Homecoming; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.)
- Effinger High School, 1925-2012 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Correspondence; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.)
- Effinger High School, 1938-1960; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.); Hotinger, Clarence (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Newspapers; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.); Farming. Rockbridge County, Virginia.
- Effinger High School, 1940-1959; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 3, Folder 35)
  Printed ephemera
- Effinger School Rosters, 1925-2011 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.)
- Introducing Rockbridge County, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  Virginia -- Rockbridge County
- Lexington Gazette Copies, 1925-1935; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Miscellaneous Printed Ephemera, 1977-2011 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Newspapers, 1972-1973; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Newspapers, 1986-2011; Lexington Gazette. (Lexington, Va.) (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Photographs, Sometime around the 1950s; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 3, Folder 42)
  Photographs
- Photographs, Sometime around the 1950s; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.) (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Photographs, 1909-1987 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  Photographs; Virginia -- Rockbridge County; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.)
- Photographs, 1950s (Box 4, Folder 45)
  Photographs; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.)
- Photographs, 2004-2010 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Photographs, 20th Century (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Parent Teacher Association, 1987-2008 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Parent Teacher Association, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Rapps Church, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  History; Rapps Church (Lexington, Va.)
- Rockbridge County Education, 1959-1980 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  Virginia -- Rockbridge County; Effinger School (Rockbridge Co., Va.)
- R. W. Hotinger, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  Genealogy; Hotinger, R. W.
- Effinger school history, Rockbridge County teacher history, some Anderson genealogy (Box 4, Folder 53)
  Scope and Contents
  This folder contains handwritten notebook pages of informaiton regarding the lineage of Effinger School with dates. Lists of family and or frieds death between 1958 ad 1972. Also lists of merit pins awarded to Rockbridge County, Va. teachers by the Rockbridge Education Association from 1950 - 1972, teachers who had retired and and those who had died within that range.